<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trang Bui</title>
    <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trang Bui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Trang Bui</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tqtbui.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Featuring</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/featuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/featuring/</guid>
      <description>Some news and online articles featuring me.
 My paper: General Additive Network Effect Model was featured in the “Design and Analysis of Experiments for Data Science” webinar by the New England Journal of Statistics in Data Science. I won the Student Research Presentation Awards in Business and Industrial Statistics and the First Prize in Case Studies in Data Analysis Poster Competition at the SSC Annual Meeting, 2023. I appeared on the news of the Statistical Consulting and Survey Research Unit for my collaborative paper on tax fairness and tax compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/teaching/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/teaching/courses/</guid>
      <description> Analytic Methods for Business 2 Spring 2022. Syllabus  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Resources</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/book/online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/book/online-resources/</guid>
      <description> Topics in Statistical Consulting - coauthored and edited with SCCRU at University of Waterloo. A First Course in Statistics - wrote based on my lecture notes for AFM 113, Spring 2022 at University of Waterloo.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/research/papers/</guid>
      <description>Methodology Papers
 General additive network effects model - with Stefan H. Steiner and Nathaniel T. Stevens. New England Journal of Statistics and Data Science (2023), 1-19, doi 10.51387/23-NEJSDS29.  Applied Papers
  Understanding the Impact of Seasonal Climate Change on Canada&amp;rsquo;s Economy by Region and Sector - with Shiyu He, Yuying Huang, Wenling Zhang, Jie Jian, Samuel W.K. Wong, and Tony S. Wirjanto. Submitted to Journal of Sustainable Finance &amp;amp; Investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/book/book-recommendation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/book/book-recommendation/</guid>
      <description>Van der Vaart, A. W. (2000). Asymptotic statistics (Vol. 3). Cambridge University Press. Howell, D. C. (2012). Statistical methods for psychology. Cengage Learning. Douglas, C. M. (2012). Design and analysis of experiments. John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons Ltd. Atkinson, A., Donev, A., &amp;amp; Tobias, R. (2007). Optimum experimental designs, with SAS. OUP Oxford. McCulloch, C. E., &amp;amp; Searle, S. R. (2004). Generalized, linear, and mixed models. John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons. Seber, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/research/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/research/talks/</guid>
      <description>  Statistical Society of Canada Annual Meeting 2023, Analytic Approaches for Novel Data Sources. General Linear Network Effects Model.
 Won the Business and Industrial Statistics Section Student Research Oral Presentation Award.      Virtual ISI World Statistics Congress 2021, IPS69, General Linear Network Effects Model for Network Experimentation.
  Student Seminar Series UWaterloo 2020, Introduction to Experimental Design on Networks.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial packages</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/projects/r/r-tutorial-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/projects/r/r-tutorial-package/</guid>
      <description>Below are R packages that I developed for the sole purpose of studying. Thus they will not be maintained. The codes are well-commented for step-by-step understanding of algorithms. These can be used for teaching or self-studying.
  varngc: Penalized regressions on Vector Autoregressive models. The loss functions used include penalized least square and penalized log-likelihood. The penalty include lasso and group lasso. This package is parallelizable.
  t.regression: Contains regression models from UWaterloo&amp;rsquo;s STAT844 course instructed by Professor Liang Kun, adapted from the lecture notes of Professor Wayne Oldford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for Ph.D. students</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/blogs/phd-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/blogs/phd-exp/</guid>
      <description>I recently submitted my thesis, which marks the end of my long and hard Ph.D. journey. Reflecting on my bumpy road, there are something I wish I knew. I think it will be beneficial to share my thoughts, in case they can help someone.
  The most important keys for success in any field is persistence and consistency. It will be very helpful to have a good working routine, diet and exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Deep Learning good?</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/blogs/why-dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/miscs/blogs/why-dl/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the David Sprott&amp;rsquo;s Distinguished Lecture by Professor Trevor Hastie and the question raised by Professor Ali Ghodsi in the Q&amp;amp;A session today, I realized several things about Deep Learning. I think there are three main reasons why they are so good:
 Deep Learning is like a stack of simpler models. Simple models, such as linear models, are ensembled together into a certain, probably hierarchical, structure. Thus, Deep Learning models usually contain many more parameters than other classical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Assistant</title>
      <link>https://tqtbui.github.io/teaching/ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tqtbui.github.io/teaching/ta/</guid>
      <description>During my graduate study at University of Waterloo, I work as a teaching assistant for many courses. Below is the list of courses that I have assisted.
 ACTSC 231 Introductory Financial Mathematics Spring 2018. STAT 202 Introductory Statistics for Scientists Fall 2017. STAT 211 Introductory Statistics and Sampling for Accounting Winter 2019. STAT 230 Probability Fall 2018, Winter 2018. STAT 316 Introduction to Statistical Problem Solving by Computer Winter 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
